datacash.com 2011-03-17

# DataCash Processing Secure Internet Payments (Credit and Debit Card, Direct Debit, Online Cash)

## 1 Introduction 

1.1 DataCash Limited (DataCash) takes the privacy of your information very seriously. This policy explains how and for what purposes DataCash uses the information collected about its customers and clients via this web site www.datacash.com (Website). In respect of data processed by DataCash on behalf of its customers and clients, please refer to our terms and conditions of business.

1.2 Please read this privacy policy carefully. By using the Website and any service that we offer whether via the Website or otherwise, you are agreeing to be bound by this policy in respect of the information collected by DataCash about you whether collected via this Website or otherwise.

1.3 If you have any queries about the policy, please get in touch with us using the contact details set out at paragraph 7 below and we will do our best to answer any queries that you may have.

## 2 Personal information collected

2.1 We will collect the following personal information from you:

2.1.1 Name;

2.1.2 Contact details (including e-mail address, postal address and telephone number);

2.1.3 Job title; and

2.1.4 Details of, where relevant, the company or business that you are employed by/represent (including financial and banking details); together (Personal Data). 

2.2 DataCash collects Personal Data to enable it to process any application for DataCash services and to communicate with you generally regarding any matter relating to the provision of DataCash services. DataCash also collects Personal Data for the purpose of informing you of any other services which DataCash or other carefully selected third parties offers which DataCash believes will be of interest to you.

2.3 Although it is not compulsory to give us the information detailed above, if you do not then we may not be able to provide you with comprehensive answers to any queries that you may have or with the full range of services that DataCash has to offer.

2.4 We may also collect (even if you do not provide any Personal Data to us) information about where you are on the internet (e.g. the URL you came from, IP address, domain types like .co.uk and .com), your browser type, the pages of the Website that were viewed during your visit, the advertisements you clicked on and any search terms that you entered on the Website (User Information). We collect this information to help us administer the Website and to provide you with a more effective service.

2.5 DataCash may also collect Personal Data from you through the use of enquiry and feedback forms from time to time. 

2.6 The internet is not a secure medium however all data that you provide to us is sent via a secure link, encrypted using standard encryption technology.

2.7 We will treat all your Personal Data as confidential (although we reserve the right to disclose this information in the circumstances set out below). We will keep it on a secure server and have implemented technology and policies to safeguard your privacy from unauthorised access and improper use. We will fully comply with all applicable UK Data Protection laws and, where relevant, consumer legislation from time to time in place. DataCash's security procedures mean that we may request proof of identity before we are able to disclose information to you.

2.8 We will take all reasonable care, in so far as it is in our power to do so, to keep the details of your Personal Data secure, but in the absence of negligence on our part we cannot be held liable for any loss you may suffer if a third party procures unauthorised access to any Personal Data you provide when accessing the Website. 

2.9 You should be aware that this Website is monitored and may capture information about your visit for the purpose of helping us to improve the quality of the services that we provide. DataCash may also perform statistical analyses in order to measure trends (for development purposes) and to inform other third parties, where relevant, as to how many customers and clients have seen or followed links to their sites. In performing these statistical analyses DataCash will disclose information to third parties only in aggregate form. If you prefer that your Personal Data is not used in this way please notify us via the contact details at paragraph 7 below.

2.10 We aim to keep Personal Data as accurate as possible. If you would like to review or change the details you have supplied us with, please contact us at the email address or telephone number set out in paragraph 7 below.

2.11 DataCash will provide details of the Personal Data held by it in respect of an individual upon request from that individual and payment of the relevant fee. To obtain such information please submit a request to us via the contact details at paragraph 7 below.

## 3 Use of Personal Data and User Information

3.1 We confirm that any Personal Data which you provide to us (or which is available on public registers) and any User Information from which we can identify you, is held in accordance with the registration that we have with the Data Commissioner's Office, and is used for the following purposes: 

3.1.1 to allow us to respond to enquiries and queries raised by you; 

3.1.2 to verify your identity;

3.1.3 to provide you with any services that you request (this may involve providing some details about you to third parties - should this become necessary we will advise you of our intention to disclose your Personal Data and the nature of such disclosure);

3.1.4 to obtain your views or comments on the services we provide;

3.1.5 for statistical purposes to improve the Website and our services to you; and

3.1.6 to administer the Website.

3.2 Additionally, if you consent by ticking the box on the [pricing page](http://www.datacash.com/about/pricing.php) at [www.datacash.com](http://www.datacash.com/) we may notify you of services (whether provided by us or some other third party) that may be of interest to you. Your consent is for us to contact you for any of the above purposes whether by telephone, e-mail or by post and to confirm that you do not consider any of the above as being a breach of any of your rights under the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003.

3.3 You may unsubscribe from our contact list at any time by replying to a promotional communication with the word "unsubscribe" in the subject line (where such communication is by e-mail), by e-mailing us at unsubscribe@datacash.com or by telephoning us on 0870 727 4761 between 9.00 am and 5.30 pm Monday to Friday.

3.4 Your Personal Data may be disclosed to other businesses within the DataCash group of companies and to reputable third parties who will assist in the provision of services to you. DataCash requires all such companies and third parties to treat your personal information as confidential and to fully comply with all applicable UK Data Protection laws and, where applicable, consumer legislation from time to time in place. 

3.5 We may transfer Personal Data to a third party as part of a sale of some or all of our business and assets to a third party or as part of any business restructuring or reorganisation, but we will take steps with the aim of ensuring that your privacy rights continue to be protected.

3.6 You should be aware that if we are requested by the police or any other regulatory or government authority investigating suspected illegal activities to provide your Personal Data and /or User Information we are entitled do so.

## 4 Your Consent

By submitting your information you consent to the use of that information as set out in this policy. If we change our privacy policy we will post the changes on this page (and may place notices on other pages of the Website) so that you will be aware of the information we collect and how we use it at all times. Continued use of the service will signify that you agree to any such changes.

## 5 Cookies

5.1 When you visit the Website we may store some information (commonly known as a "cookie") on your computer. Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to your hard drive to store and sometimes track information about you. Cookies are specific to the server that created them and cannot be accessed by other servers, which means that they cannot be used to track your movements around the web. Passwords and credit card numbers are not stored in cookies. A cookie helps you get the best out of the Website and helps us to provide you with a more customised service. We use cookies for the following purposes:

5.1.1 so that you will not have to re-enter your details each time you visit the Website; and

5.1.2 to track how our site is used and to improve and update the content of the Website.

5.2 You can block or erase cookies from your computer if you want to (your browser's help screen or manual should tell you how to do this), but certain parts of the Website are reliant on the use of cookies to operate correctly and may not work correctly if you set your browser not to accept cookies.

## 6 Linking to third party websites

6.1 We cannot be responsible for the privacy polices of other sites even if you access them using links from the Website and recommend that you check the policy of each site you visit and contact its owner or operator if you have any concerns or questions.

6.2 In addition, if you linked to the Website from a third party site, we cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of the owners or operators of that third party site and recommend that you check the policy of that third party site and contact its owner or operator if you have any concerns or questions.

## 7 Contact us

If at any time you would like to contact us with your views about our privacy practices, or with any enquiry relating to your Personal Data, you can do so by sending an email to us at [info@datacash.com](mailto:info@datacash.com), telephoning us on 0870 727 4761 or writing to us at DataCash Ltd, 8 Gate Street, London, WC2A 3HP.
